<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My Protanopic Life - photographology</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://protanopic.com/feeds/photographology.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://protanopic.com/</id><updated>2012-04-18T13:57:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>On Lightfield photography and Lytro</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/on-lightfield-photography-and-lytro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-18T13:57:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-18T13:57:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2012-04-18:/on-lightfield-photography-and-lytro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Warde commenting on Lytro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewers will find clicking on photos to refocus them to be fun for
exactly 17 seconds, after which theyll be bored, not to mention
annoyed that they're being made to do work the photographer should
have done already.  As for the folks behind the camera …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Warde commenting on Lytro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewers will find clicking on photos to refocus them to be fun for
exactly 17 seconds, after which theyll be bored, not to mention
annoyed that they're being made to do work the photographer should
have done already.  As for the folks behind the camera, placing the
focus is a creative decision, and in general, photographers aren't
going to want the end viewer making their creative decisions for
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear, I'm not skeptical about the value of being able to
set focus after the fact, I'm only skeptical about the value of
letting the viewer set focus after the fact.  Letting the
photographer set focus after the fact is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cameracuriosities.com/2012/04/lytro-its-aliiiiiive.html"&gt;Camera Curiosities: Lytro - Its
Aliiiiiive!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with this completely. I was really excited about the technology
behind the Lytro camera, but I had never thought of letting the
viewer be the one to set focus. I had envisioned it to enable more
creative control in post-production. I canceled my Lytro order without
a solid reason why, but this article put into words what I had felt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Every World Press Photo Winner From 1955-2011</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/every-world-press-photo-winner-from-1955-2011.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-23T21:03:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-02-23T21:03:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2012-02-23:/every-world-press-photo-winner-from-1955-2011.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are some *incredible* photos that tell amazing stories
here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/mjs538/every-world-press-photo-winner-from-1955-2011"&gt;Every World Press Photo Winner From
1955-2011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry><entry><title>Exploring HDR processing of a single RAW image</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-23T17:53:00-07:00</published><updated>2011-10-23T17:53:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2011-10-23:/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You don't have to research HDR much to find the common questions about
how best to process a single image into an HDR. Some people suggest
taking the photo and running it straight through Photomatix, letting it
do all the legwork. Others suggest taking the image into something like
Lightroom …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You don't have to research HDR much to find the common questions about
how best to process a single image into an HDR. Some people suggest
taking the photo and running it straight through Photomatix, letting it
do all the legwork. Others suggest taking the image into something like
Lightroom and exporting different versions of the image with the
exposures set at the different increments to mimic exposure bracketed
shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long, long time I was in the first camp. The thinking says simply
that by adjusting the exposure you're not adding anything to the image.
It suggests that since all of the data is contained in the original
image, exporting differently exposed versions of the same photo is just
presenting that data in a different way.  However, I have recently
discovered that this assumption is wrong. Amazingly, many of my
assumptions on what was happening with the data in my photographs turned
out to be wrong, and overly generous. I put too much faith in the
software, assuming it would do things in the most efficient way because
that was the ideal way to do it.  Unfortunately, the truth is that
Photoshop and Photomatix do terrible things to your photographic data,
and I will show you this fact here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I was on a boat with my wife, and as is normal in San
Francisco summers the fog was rolling in past the Golden Gate Bridge.
There was a lot of movement on the boat so I couldn't take a bracketed
set. I didn't care though. I assumed Photomatix would let me balance
these extreme lighting conditions with no sweat. The photos I took on
that boat were the beginning of my discovery that I was giving
Photomatix too much credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an original photo taken on the boat with a Canon T3i at 14bpp
raw:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4459&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-2/"&gt;&lt;img alt="The untouched file, default settings." class="size-medium wp-image-4459" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-2-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The untouched file, default
settings.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not immediately obvious that the The Golden Gate Bridge is in the
background, but you can barely see it on the left. This type of
situation is where I was hoping that Photomatix would solve my exposure
balance problems. When I looked at the RAW file in Lightroom and dropped
the exposure down I could see the bridge.  I imported the single image
into Photomatix Pro 4.1 and did a default tonemap, hoping to bring out
the details that were lost in the highlights. Here's what Photomatix
produced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4458&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40_tonemapped_dng/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tonemapped from DNG in Photomatix using default settings" class="size-medium wp-image-4458" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40_tonemapped_DNG-300x199.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 199px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Tonemapped from DNG in Photomatix using default settings[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's interesting, but it's not exactly helpful.  Specifically, you
still can't see the bridge and other features that exist in the RAW
data.  In its place is a smooth, unrealistic, grey sludge.  Clearly
Photomatix has thrown away some important data that would have been very
useful.  At this moment I realized that the technique of exporting a
single RAW image with different exposure settings in fact does allow you
to create better HDR images in Photomatix because it was obvious to me
at that point that Photomatix was throwing away useful data when working
with data from a single RAW file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing an hour or so of research on gamut and image formats, trying
to get a grasp on their differences, I thought &amp;quot;my camera is only 14
bits per pixel, but PSD can be 16 bits per pixel, so surely it must be
able to store all the extra information that Photomatix is throwing
away!&amp;quot;  I converted the DNG to a PSD, imported that into Photomatix, ran
it through the default tone map settings can came out with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4457&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-2_tonemapped_psd/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tonemapped in Photomatix from PSD using default settings" class="size-medium wp-image-4457" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-2_tonemapped_PSD-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Tonemapped in Photomatix from PSD using default settings[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that many of the important details are still missing,
this image is better than what I got while running the DNG file straight
into Photomatix.  This means that Photomatix is bad at handling what is
purported to be THE raw format for digital photographs from all
manufacturers, the Digital Negative.  DNG supports data from more RAW
images formats and more types of metadata than any other format.  There
is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adobe.com/support/downloads/detail.jsp?ftpID=4924"&gt;free
converter&lt;/a&gt; with
a graphical UI and a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wwwimages.adobe.com/www.adobe.com/content/dam/Adobe/en/products/photoshop/pdfs/dng_commandline.pdf"&gt;scriptable CLI
interface&lt;/a&gt;,
a freely available
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adobe.com/support/downloads/dng/dng_sdk.html"&gt;SDK&lt;/a&gt;, and
it even has the ability to store the original RAW file inside of the DNG
in case you simply don't trust what it's doing with your RAW data.  It's
remarkable that even with all of that available, Photomatix still can't
transpose the 14 bit raw data into a 32 bit radiance file without losing
significant amounts of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought it was peculiar is how Photoshop itself was unable to
show the extra data.  When I converted the DNG into PSD, I had similar
results as I did with the DNG file.  This led me to do another hour or
so of research, and I eventually found out what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAW data is storing information about all of the light that came into
the camera and hit the sensor.  This data includes parts of the image
that are outside the perceptive range of your eyes at any, shall we say,
iris exposure setting.  That is, when the iris of your eye opens and
closes, it allows you to see brighter or dimmer things, but you cannot
see the whole range of luminance at once.  Your eyes are limited to a
medium to low dynamic range, thus the need for HDR and tone-mapping to
display all of the information.  RAW images store data that is beyond
the limits of the whitest white and the blackest black that you can see
in a properly exposed RAW photograph.  Photomatix also has several
formats in its arsenal that are also supposed to do that, and they very
well may do so, but that's beyond the scope of this article.  PSD does
not store this extra data.  Tiff doesn't either.  JPG certainly does
not.  These image formats are storing color values between white and
black.  White is the brightest point that your eyes can see and can be
displayed, and no information past that point is stored.  Black is the
darkest area your eyes can see, and no information beyond that point is
stored.  These formats are rasterized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, this explains why you can't gain anything if you were
allowed to convert rasterized image like PSD or JPG into a DNG file.
Since you're not gaining any extra data when you attempt to convert a
rasterized file to a RAW file, you might as well just use a TIFF or PSD,
and in fact the DNG Converter will not let you create a DNG from
anything but a RAW file format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's interesting to me is that professional photo editing resources
toss this rather important detail out all the time and put PSD and DNG
on the same level.  Matt Kloskowski from Adobe constantly gets hassled
at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lightroomkillertips.com/"&gt;Lightroom Killer Tips&lt;/a&gt; for going
back and forth between Lightroom, an app with a purely RAW format based
workflow, and Photoshop, which works with rasterized data which
truncates lots of important information from both extremes of the
radiance spectrum.  Professionals like Matt are, in essence, teaching us
techniques that are severely sub-optimal and disregarding this data loss
issue entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Professional applications like Adobe Photoshop and Photomatix
Pro are also silently truncating important data at both ends of the
radiance spectrum when they are supposed to be doing exactly the
opposite.  Photomatix has one primary purpose, to compress images that
have a wide radiance down into images of narrow radiance so our eyes can
see the features beyond our visual perception.  Nobody who uses this app
expects it to simply throw away the parts of the image that can't be
seen.  If we needed that, we'd shoot in JPG or TIFF and use
shadow/highlight in Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all of this thinking and researching, I did a final
experiment. I used Lightroom to create three versions of the same image
and merged them in Photomatix Pro as if I had taken an exposure
bracketed set.  The three images are -4EV, 0EV, +4EV. Only the exposure
was changed, and the watermark wasn't included in the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4460&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-1/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Adjusted in LR to -4EV" class="size-medium wp-image-4460" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-1-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Adjusted in LR to -4EV[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4459&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-2/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Default settings in LR, 0EV" class="size-medium wp-image-4459" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-2-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Default settings in LR,
0EV[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4461&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-3/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Adjusted in LR to +4EV" class="size-medium wp-image-4461" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-3-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Adjusted in LR to +4EV[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I merged these in Photomatix and used the same default tone-mapping
settings as the previous photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4456&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://protanoptic.com/2011/10/23/exploring-hdr-processing-of-a-single-raw-image/20110702-17-15-40-1_2_3_fused/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tonemapped from PSD's at -4EV, 0EV and +4EV in Photomatix using default settings" class="size-medium wp-image-4456" src="http://protanoptic.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/20110702-17-15-40-1_2_3_fused-300x200.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 200px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tonemapped from PSD's at -4EV, 0EV and +4EV in
Photomatix using default settings[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this final set you can see the extent of the information that was
being thrown out by Photoshop and Photomatix.  Specifically, the entire
Golden Gate Bridge was captured by the camera, but was invisible to both
applications using their standard import methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, I am now on the side of the people who recommend
exporting exposure bracketed versions of a single exposure when using
Photomatix to tonemap a single image. Science, logic and truth prevail,
revealing to everybody the Golden Gate Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry><entry><title>Rethinking Photography in 2011</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/rethinking-photography-in-2011.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-26T16:24:00-07:00</published><updated>2011-04-26T16:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2011-04-26:/rethinking-photography-in-2011.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday some mixed feelings and vague thoughts I've been having for a
long time culminated in the decision to sell all of my photography gear
and start over from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been a hobbyist photographer for a long time, I got my first camera
when I was about 7, but …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday some mixed feelings and vague thoughts I've been having for a
long time culminated in the decision to sell all of my photography gear
and start over from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been a hobbyist photographer for a long time, I got my first camera
when I was about 7, but in 2009 I quit my tech job and began putting
more focus on doing photography as a career.  What I found out about
myself over the course of many months is that I'm not one of those
people who likes to go into business for himself, and I wouldn't be very
good at it. I'm too altruistic and have such a relative sense of worth
that it's very hard for me to make money by selling art. Plus I hate
selling, greatness should sell itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from not being good at business, I found it hard to find people to
work with. It seems like so many people talk and dream but few people
actually produce. This was incredibly frustrating to me because I wanted
to produce night and day, and had had that chance when living at 4211
with a gaggle of fashionistas living next door, the beach a block away,
Rob always dragging me to punk rock shows, the rise of flashmob scene,
and newbie exploration of the San Francisco festivals. Then after that I
went off to travel and found unlimited things to photograph in SE Asia,
and came back to America to focus on professional and fashion
photography. However, the lack of interested parties and paying clients
led me to retreat to the more lucrative technology sector, and the
frequency of photo shoots dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that while, the landscape of professional photography was changing.
The number of decent to good cameras in the hands of average consumers
skyrocketed. The iPhone 4 and its awesome camera was released, DSLR
prices dropped while sensor technology got better. Micro 4/3 cameras
took off. Cameras are now everywhere. This meant the bar to entering
photography was lower, and in turn many people showed that they had a
natural talent for photography. These people were not professionals but
they were posting amazing quality work online, then giving it away for
free to companies who would've had to pay just a few years earlier.
Companies don't need to pay for photography anymore, they just browse
the creative commons area of Flickr, ask for commercial rights and get
it. When they do pay, it's a fraction of what they would've had to pay
before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, I see people with charisma and capital but little
talent for photography out there shooting mediocre work and blogging
about it and posting in every Flickr pool that requires comments and
fav's, gathering a following of praising people who don't know great
artistic photography from a computer animated dog food commercial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I was carrying around a bunch of heavy, expensive,
professional, photography gear doing my hobby thing, getting a few paid
gigs here and there on the side. I was halfway in my professional
photography mindset and halfway in my hobby mindset; living two lives. I
feel like this has been a big distraction to my tech profession and my
personal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is technology advances. Cameras are changing. They have been
mostly the same for a long time, but now we have iPhone apps that create
panoramas inside of a phone where previously you'd have to take a shift
lens or a land camera out to do architectural work. The cameras inside
these phones suck compared to SLRs, but things like in-cam HDR
generation and auto-stitching apps give them higher level skills. Of
course, they aren't approaching H4D level, but there's no doubt that the
camera on a phone can produce images that are stunning. After all, the
best camera is the one you have on you, and now almost everybody has
one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a lot of it boils down to me taking photography too seriously. I
have a serious hobby, but it's not a profession. Hobbies are supposed to
be fun and enriching. With the failure of my attempted photography
career, I think it's time to start over, so that's what I'm doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="photography"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Quick flickr tip about shutter actuation count</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/quick-flickr-tip-about-shutter-actuation-count.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-14T20:16:00-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-14T20:16:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2010-11-14:/quick-flickr-tip-about-shutter-actuation-count.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you want to see how many photos your camera has taken, take a photo
and upload it to Flickr, then look at the EXIF data.  The &amp;quot;Image Number&amp;quot;
field is the number of shutter actuations of the camera body that took
the photo.  This is a useful piece of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you want to see how many photos your camera has taken, take a photo
and upload it to Flickr, then look at the EXIF data.  The &amp;quot;Image Number&amp;quot;
field is the number of shutter actuations of the camera body that took
the photo.  This is a useful piece of information when reselling a
selling used gear, and generally neat to know if you take a lot of
photos.  I'm adding a graph of actuations vs time to my to-do list for
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flixplor.com"&gt;flixplor.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="flickr"></category></entry><entry><title>Stereoscopy</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/stereoscopy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-08-30T13:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-30T13:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2009-08-30:/stereoscopy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;address&gt;&lt;p&gt;3D photography is something I've been in and out of for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/address&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="glossary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Glossary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/30th rule - The separation between the perspective of the two
images should be 1/30th the distance to the nearest subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cha-cha - A method of taking 3d photos where you use one camera to
take …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;address&gt;&lt;p&gt;3D photography is something I've been in and out of for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/address&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="glossary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Glossary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/30th rule - The separation between the perspective of the two
images should be 1/30th the distance to the nearest subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cha-cha - A method of taking 3d photos where you use one camera to
take two photographs, one for the left and one for the right, by
moving the camera to each location.  This can be done with a slide
bar or by just shifting your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross view - A stereograph where the left eye is on the right of the
image and the right eye is on the left of the image. Most people find
these photos easier to view, especially in larger sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual Cameras - The use of two cameras, usually identical hardware, to
capture a both images of a stereograph at one time.  A synchronous
trigger such as hardware mods or an IR remote are often used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallel view - A stereograph where the left eye and right eye are
presented as the world is seen naturally.  Your eyes look parallel to
each other to see the 3d image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide bar - A tool used for increased precision when taking cha-cha
stereographs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stereo Baseline - The horizontal distance between the two images
taken, basically the distance between your eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stereo Camera - A camera made for taking stereo photographs, such as
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.fujifilm.com/products/3d/camera/finepix_real3dw1/"&gt;Fujifilm FinePix REAL 3D
W1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="links"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.3dphoto.net/forum/"&gt;3dphoto.net/forum&lt;/a&gt; - A lot of
great information from DIYers can be found in the forums here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ledametrix.com/index.html"&gt;ledametrix.com&lt;/a&gt; - Lots of
good information, examples, and information on different stereoscopic
still photography gear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stereoscopy"&gt;Wikipedia -
Stereoscopy&lt;/a&gt; covers a
lot of the aspects of stereoscopy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stereoscopy.com/jasper/slide-bars.html"&gt;Jasper slide
bars&lt;/a&gt; - These
appear to be the best slide bars, though I've never used them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.f295.org/Pinholeforum/forum/Blah.pl?m-1166543630/"&gt;f29 - wo0den
slidebar&lt;/a&gt;
is a cheap, simple DIY slidebar that looks very promising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="loreo-3d-lens-in-a-cap"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loreo 3d Lens in a Cap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.loreo.com/pages/products/loreo_3dcap.html"&gt;Loreo 3d Lens in a
Cap&lt;/a&gt; with the
expectation that it would be a fun little toy.  Indeed it is, but it was
remarkably difficult to use with much success.  It failed with the two
feature incompatibilities of being zoomed in too tight for its stereo
base line and too limited in its near focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perspective of the lens makes it difficult to photograph large
things without standing very far away from them.  Coupled with the
narrow baseline and the 1/30th rule this defeats the purpose of shooting
in stereo.  So, this lens doesn't work well for shooting large objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The near focus of this lens is limited to something greater than about a
meter.  This means you can't photograph things up close, there is no
macro ability.  you can photograph something like a basketball and have
good composition, but not something like an action figure because there
would be a lot of extra extra space around the subject.  Since you can't
crop the image easily it makes for compositionally poor images for small
objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/warzauwynn/3871828236/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Golden Blake Bridge" class="align-right" src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2578/3871828236_a8d91b9ff5_n.jpg" style="width: 320px; height: 213px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The result is basically a long portrait lens with
an ƒ/11 aperture.  ƒ/11 is not the best aperture for portraits with a
lot of bokeh, and if you want to have a secondary subject in the
distance you still have have to stand a long way away from it.  For
instance, this photo of Blake was taken many miles form the Golden Gate
Bridge and you still can't see both sides of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a rumor that Loreo is working on a lens with a wider focal
length.  This would probably solve both of the problems listed above,
and would certainly solve a least the narrow perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I wouldn't recommend buying the Loreo because of these
limitations.  If you happen to find one for cheap or want to borrow one
that could be fun, but otherwise I'd seek out other methods for
stereoscopy like the simple cha-cha method or picking up two cheap
pocket cams or webcams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="photographology"></category></entry></feed>