<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My Protanopic Life - technology</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://protanopic.com/feeds/technology.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://protanopic.com/</id><updated>2016-11-25T11:37:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Technological aspects of protanopic.com - 2016 edition</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/technological-aspects-of-protanopic-com-2016-edition.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-25T11:37:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-25T11:37:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Hoherd</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2016-11-25:/technological-aspects-of-protanopic-com-2016-edition.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, my site has gone through a massive transformation so I thought I'd write
a bit about it, seeing as how I wrote about it back in 2009 when I was first
putting it up on Wordpress. Over the years I found myself disabling several of
the dynamic features like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, my site has gone through a massive transformation so I thought I'd write
a bit about it, seeing as how I wrote about it back in 2009 when I was first
putting it up on Wordpress. Over the years I found myself disabling several of
the dynamic features like page comments. I was also &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.sucuri.net/2010/07/understanding-and-cleaning-the-pharma-hack-on-wordpress.html"&gt;hacked&lt;/a&gt; with an attack that
stored the exploit inside of the database. This was an interesting attack
because my page appeared fine to everybody except google bots. I also found
that doing mass modifications of posts was difficult using the wordpress UI. To
work around this I thought I might look into using the Wordpress API, but by
this time I was pretty much done wanting to write PHP. The web host that I had
been using for over 10 years had been slowly reducing its features and had
passed a point where it was worth paying for. So, during a Yelp hackathon in
November 2016 I migrated all of my old wordpress content to Pelican, a static
blogging engine written in Python. I moved hosting of my site from my old VPS
to Github Pages. So far it's been working out great. I've lost the ability to
write server-side dynamic features, which is something I didn't really care
about doing, but I've also lost the ability to get hacked through my db, and
gained the ability to make changes en masse using familiar filesystem level
tools like sed and whatnot. I can track changes in git, which is also very
familiar and integrates with many things. All in all I'd say this is a nearly
perfect win. The only thing I really miss is having a remote shell available
from not my house and not my work. I'm sure if I ever need one I can easily
spin up an EC2 or Digital Ocean instance to handle my needs better than my old
VPS was.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>This is not a phone. It’s a computer that makes phone calls.</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/this-is-not-a-phone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-25T10:31:50-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-25T10:31:50-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2016-11-25:/this-is-not-a-phone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bruce Schneier, addressing the House of Representatives’ Energy and
Commerce Committee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the chairman pointed out, there are now computers in everything.
But I want to suggest another way of thinking about it in that
everything is now a computer: This is not a phone. It’s a computer
that …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bruce Schneier, addressing the House of Representatives’ Energy and
Commerce Committee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the chairman pointed out, there are now computers in everything.
But I want to suggest another way of thinking about it in that
everything is now a computer: This is not a phone. It’s a computer
that makes phone calls. A refrigerator is a computer that keeps
things cold. ATM machine is a computer with money inside. Your car
is not a mechanical device with a computer. It’s a computer with
four wheels and an engine… And this is the Internet of Things, and
this is what caused the DDoS attack we’re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come from the world of 'computer' security, and that is now
'everything' security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dailydot.com/layer8/bruce-schneier-internet-of-things/"&gt;Bruce Schneier: 'The internet era of fun and games is over'&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="technology"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Technological aspects of protanopic.com - 2009 edition</title><link href="https://protanopic.com/technological-aspects-of-protanopiccom.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-05-14T15:13:00-07:00</published><updated>2009-05-14T15:13:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel</name></author><id>tag:protanopic.com,2009-05-14:/technological-aspects-of-protanopiccom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new site is coming along quickly due to the ease of installation
provided by Wordpress and the awesome extension and theme communities
build around it. Open source software is so rad. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished integrating Facebook into the commenting system (via the
Disqus.com plugin), which lets you comment …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new site is coming along quickly due to the ease of installation
provided by Wordpress and the awesome extension and theme communities
build around it. Open source software is so rad. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished integrating Facebook into the commenting system (via the
Disqus.com plugin), which lets you comment on posts without having to
make an account or anything silly like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I have not yet found a solution for is the ability to geotag
each post. In LiveJournal, there is a &amp;quot;location&amp;quot; text entry box when you
compose a new post which lets you put any type of location data in
there, from a street address to a lat/lon waypoint. I can't find
anything like that for Wordpress though and I'd really like to show a
map or have a google earth page that shows where I wrote blog entries
and where I took photos. Does anybody know of something like that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have the geotagging thing down with the photos via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/warzauwynn/map"&gt;my Flickr
map&lt;/a&gt;, it's just a matter
of integrating it with Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="technology"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="photography"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="flickr"></category></entry></feed>